Ironwood certainly loves bringing his work wherever he travels
Ironwood還真喜歡走哪就把他那些玩意兒帶哪
Well
畢竟
Running an academy and a military makes him a busy man
又辦學院又弄軍隊讓他根本停不下來
But yes, those are a bit of an eyesore
不過確實，那些玩意兒有點礙眼
Come in
進來
Ozpin!
Ozpin
Hello, General
你好，將軍
Please, drop the formalities
拜託，別這麼正式嘛
It's been too long
很久沒見了
And Glynda! It has certainly been too long since we last met
以及Glynda！上次見面還真是很久以前了
Oh, James!
好啊，James
I'll be outside
我去外頭等著
Oh, she hasn't changed a bit
哈，她一點兒也沒變
So
那麼
What in the world has brought you all the way down from Atlas?
到底什麼風把你從阿特拉斯一路吹來了？
Headmasters don't typically travel with their students, for the Vytal Festival
校長一般是不和學生們一起來參加維特節的
Well, you know how much I love Vale this time of year
你也知道我最愛每年這時候的溪谷了
Besides, with you hosting
何況是你主辦
I thought that this might be a good opportunity for us to catch up
我覺得這機會用來找你敘舊再好不過了
I can certainly appreciate the quality time between friends
我當然想跟朋友享受珍貴的時光
However, a small fleet outside my window has me somewhat concerned
但我窗外這支小型艦隊總覺得讓人憂心
Well, concerned is what brought them here
唉，就是因為憂心才把他們帶來
I understand travel between kingdoms has become increasingly difficult
我明白現在王國之間的旅行越來越難了
Oz, you and I both know why I brought those men
老奧，你我都清楚為何我要帶這些軍人來
We are in a time of peace
我們處於和平時期
Shows of power like this
展示這種力量
are just going to give off the wrong impression
只會釋放錯誤的印象給世人
But if what Qrow said is true, then..
但如果Qrow說的是真的，那麼..
If what Qrow said is true, then we will handle it tactfully
如果Qrow說的是真的，那我們會巧妙處理的
It's the Vytal Festival
這是維特節
A time to celebrate unity and peace
一個慶祝團結與和平的時刻
So I suggest that you not scare people by transporting hundreds of soldiers halfway across the continent
所以我勸你別跨半個大陸運送好幾百個戰士把路人都嚇著了
I'm just being cautious
我只是謹慎起見
As am I
我也一樣
Which is why we will continue to train the best Huntsmen and Huntresses we can
這也是為何我們一直竭盡所能培養最優秀的獵人
Believe me, I am
相信我，我在培養
But ask yourself this
但你先捫心自問
Do you honestly believe your children can win a war?
你當真相信你的孩子們能贏一場戰爭？
I hope they never have to
我希望他們根本不用去戰
All right..
很好..
All right!
就這樣
Yang Xiao Long, prepare your kingdom for battle!
Yang Xiao Long，讓你的王國準備戰鬥！
Bring it on!
放馬過來！
I deploy the Atlesian Air Fleet~
看我部署[阿特拉斯航空艦隊]~
Looks like I get to fly right over your Ursi and attack your walls directly
看樣子我可以越過你的拉丁熊直接攻擊城牆
Errrro 0w0
我飛 0w0
You fiend!
你這惡魔！
And since Atlas is part of Mantle
而且因為阿特拉斯屬於曼特爾
My repair time only lasts.. one turn
我的維修時間只要..一回合
Hahaha
哈哈哈
Pretty sneaky, sis
相當陰險啊妹子
But you just activated my trap card!
但你正好激活了我的陷阱卡！
What?!
吶尼！？
Giant Nevermore!
[巨型影魔鴉]！
If I roll a seven or higher
如果我擲一個七或更高
Fatal feathers will slice your fleet in two
致命的羽翼會把你的艦隊一分為二
But, if you roll a six or lower
但，如果你擲一個六或更低
the Nevermore will turn on your own forces
影魔鴉就會攻擊你自己的部隊
That's just a chance I'm willing to take
我很樂意冒這個險
Hah!
哈！
Naaaaaaa!
不~
My fearless soldiers!
我無畏的士兵！
And most of them are probably Androids
而且大部分都是機器人
goodbye my friends
再見了朋友們
You will be avenged QAQ
我一定給你們報仇 QAQ
Not until I draw my rewards
等我拿到獎勵再說
which are double this round, thanks to the Mistral Trade Route
這輪居然還是雙倍，感謝寒風商路
Baka!
Baka！QAQ
Oh, what's this? The Smugglers of Wind Path
哇噢這是啥？風路的走私船
They all have pancakes..
他們都有烤薄餅..
Ah~haha
啊~哈哈QvQ
Looks like I'm taking two cards from your hands
看來這次能從你手裡抽兩張牌
Have you no heart?
你的良心呢？
No~
不~
Well Weiss, it's your turn
好了Weiss，輪到你了
I have..
我..
Absolutely no idea what's going on
根本不知道是啥情況
Look, it's easy
很簡單的
You're playing as Vacuo which means all Vacuo-based cards come with a bonus
你玩的是維基亞，那麼所有維基亞的卡都會有額外效果
That sounds dumb
聽著略傻
See, you've got SandStorm, Desert Scavenge
看，你現在有[沙塵暴]、[沙漠探索]
Oh, oh! Resourceful Raider!
哦哦，有[戰術掠奪者]！
See, now you can take Ruby's discard air fleet
你就能奪來Ruby廢掉的[航空艦隊]
No TvT~
表TvT
And put it in your hand
並變成自己的活牌
Okay
好吧
And since Vacuo warriors have endurance against natural hazards
然後維基亞的兵種對自然災害有抗性
you can use SandStorm to disable my ground forces and simultaneously infiltrate my kingdom
你可以用[沙塵暴]癱瘓掉我的地面部隊同時入侵我的王國
Just know, that I will not forget this declaration of war
不過要知道，我會牢記你的宣戰
And that means..
也就是說..
You're just three moves away from conquering Remnant!
你只要再走三步就能稱霸樹不子世界了
Ah~haha haha haha haha ha
啊~哈哈 哈哈 哈哈 哈哈 哈
Yes! Fear the almighty power of my forces
很好！在我全能的部隊前顫抖吧
Cower as they pillage your homes
蜷縮著看他們掠奪你家
and weep as they take your children from your very arms!
淚目著看他們從你懷裡搶走小孩！
Trap card
陷阱卡
Huh?
誒？
Your armies have been destroyed
你全軍覆沒了
Huh, I hate this game of emotions we play
啊，我恨這玩弄感情的遊戲
Stay strong Weiss, we'll make it through this together!
堅強點Weiss，我們一起撐過去
Shut up, don't touch me
閉嘴，別蹭我 T_T
Alright Blake, you're up
好了Blake，該你了
Huh?
哈？
Oh, um..
哦，呃..
Sorry, what am I doing?
抱歉，我該幹嘛？
You're playing as Vale, trying to conquer the Kingdoms of Remnant
你玩的是溪谷，目標是征服樹不子的所有王國
Right..
對..
Hey! Can I play?
話說！我能玩麼？
Sorry Jaune, we've already got four people
抱歉Jaune，我們四個人滿了
Besides, this game requires a certain level of tactical cunning
再說了，這遊戲需要一定程度的戰略戰術
that I seriously doubt that you possess
我不相信你能玩得起來
Er, you attacked your own naval fleet two turns ago
呃，你兩回合前攻擊過自己的航海艦隊
Umm
口亨
Bring it on, Ice Queen
來啊，冰雪女王
I'll have you know that I've been told I'm a natural born leader
讓你知道我也曾經被人說過是天生領袖
By who? Your mother?
被誰？你媽媽？
And Pyrrha!
還有Pyrrha！
Hello again!
又見面了~
Come on, let me play your hand for a turn
來嘛，讓我用你的牌玩一回合
I'm not trusting you with the good citizens of Vacuo
我才不放心把維基亞的好市民交給你
Why not? You've trusted me with way more important stuff before
為啥啊？以前重要得多的事你都放心交給我過
I mean, you told us all that Blake is secretly a Fau-
比如你告訴大家Blake其實是個弗-
Fun loving person, whom we're admire and respect
富有幽默、人見人愛，我們都愛戴著她
Right, that..
沒錯，那麼..
Ladies..
女士們..
Enjoy your battle
戰得開心
Sup, losers
嗨，菜鳥們
Hey Sun!
嘿，Sun！
Ruby, Yang, Blake..
Ruby、Yang、Blake..
Ice Queen
冰雪女王
Why does everyone keep calling me that?
你們幹嘛都這麼叫我？
I never got a chance to formally introduce you to my old friend
一直沒機會向你們正式介紹我的老朋友
Uhh, aren't libraries for reading?
呃，圖書館不是讀書用的麼？
Thank you!
謝助攻！
Pancakes!
烤薄餅！
Shut, don't be a nerd
閉嘴，別當書獃子
Gee Gee Gee Gee, intellectual, okay? Thank you
喂喂喂喂，是知識分子好嗎？謝了
I'm Neptune
我叫Neptune
So Neptune
那麼Neptune
Where're you from?
你從哪兒來？
Haven
黑文
And..I don't believe I've caught your name
然後..我還不知道你的名字呢
Snow Angel
白雪天使
Um, I'm Weiss
呃，我叫Weiss
Are you kidding me?!
這是在逗我！？
Pleasure to meet you
很榮幸認識你
I never took you as the board game playing type
我從沒想過你還是棋盤遊戲玩家
Right
是啊
Well, I think I'm done playing, actually
不過，其實我不玩了
I'll see you guys later
大家待會兒見
Women
女人呀
Brothers of the White Fang!
白牙的弟兄們！
Why are you aiding this scum?
你們為何幫助這個人渣？
The White Fang and I are going in on a joint business venture together
白牙和我要共同進行一樁有風險的買賣
Well
哈
This has certianly been an eventful evening
這還真是個熱鬧的夜晚
I'm sure that after a night of thwarting attempted robbery
我相信你一晚上都在制止搶竊
you probably just want to go home and take a nap
現在估計很想回去睡個覺
But..
不過..
I was hoping that maybe we could have the chance to talk
我還是希望能有機會跟你聊聊
Of course
沒有問題
Wonderful
很好
As you know, in order to enroll at my academy
如你所知，要被我的學院錄取
students must first pass a rigorous entrance exam
學生首先要通過一個嚴苛的入學考試
Most applicants spend years of preparation
大部分申請入學的都要準備多年
training in one of the many combat schools around the world
在這滿世界的戰鬥學校裡選一個修煉
You are one of the few who did not
你是少數沒有進過戰鬥學校的
And you passed the exam with flying colors
而你卻出色地通過了考試
I was raised outside the kingdoms
我在王國外頭長大的
If you can't fight, you can't survive
若不會戰鬥，就撐不下來
Well, you have most certainly survived, Blake
而你確實是撐過來了，Blake
I admire your drive
我欽佩你的求生慾望
And I am proud to run a school that accept individuals from all walks of life
而我也很自豪我的學校能接納各界人士
Rich, poor..
富裕的，貧困的..
Human..
人類..
Faunus..
弗納人..
Why do you wear that bow, Blake?
為何要戴蝴蝶結，Blake？
Why hide who you are?
為何要隱藏自己？
You may be willing to accept the Faunus, Professor Ozpin
你可能願意接納弗納人，Ozpin教授
But your species is not
但你的同族卻不會
True
確實
But we are continuing to take strides to lessen the divide
但我們一直在朝化解分歧方向前進
With all due respect
請恕我直言
You need to start taking some larger strides
你需要加大前進的步伐
Until then, I'd rather avoid any unnecessary attention
在那之前，我寧願迴避任何不必要的注意
I want people to see me for who I am
我想讓人們關注我本身
Not what I am
而不是我的身份
And what are you?
那你是什麼身份？
I.. I don't understand what you're asking
我..我不明白你的問題
How did you know the White Fang would be at the shipyard tonight?
你是如何得知白牙今晚會去船廠的？
I didn't
我不知道
I just happened to be at the right place at the right time
我只是碰巧在那裡了而已
You wouldn't have been the first
你也不是第一個了
But what happened tonight was not an isolated incident
但今晚發生的，並非獨立事件
I may be your headmaster
我算是你校長
but I am also a Huntsman
但我也是個獵人
and it is my sworn duty to protect this world from the forces that conspire against it
從那些密謀要對抗這個世界的勢力中保護她是我的神聖職責
Blake
Blake
Are you sure there is nothing else you would like to tell me?
你確定沒有其他想要告訴我的東西了？
I'm sure
確定
Very well
那很好
Thank you for your time, Ms. Belladonna
多謝你能抽時間，Belladonna女士
If you ever need to talk to me
你若需要跟我談話
Please, don't hesitate to ask
請千萬別猶豫
Ugh, we should've never let him play!
呃，就不該讓他玩的！
You just mad cuz the new guy beat you
你只是敗給他了才生氣
See, if you had just attacked when I told you, none of this would've happened
你當時聽我的進攻了的話，就根本沒這些破事了
Stop
站住
Lately you've been quiet and antisocial and moody
你最近既安靜又不善交際還喜怒無常
Uh, have you met Blake?
呃，你是第一次認識Blake麼？
Which I get, is kind of your thing
我知道那是你本性
But you've been doing it more than usual
但你比平常更陰沉了
Which quite frankly, is unacceptable!
說句老實話，我忍不住了
You made a promise to me
你跟我保證過
to all of us, that you would let us know if something was wrong
跟大家都保證過，若有事發生要告訴我們
So, Blake Belladonna
那麼，Blake Belladonna
What..
到底..
is..
什麼..
wrong?!
事！？
I just..
我只是..
I don't understand how everyone can be so calm
我不明白怎麼所有人都能如此淡定
You're still thinking about Torchwick?
你依然在顧慮 Torchwick？
Torchwick, the White Fang, all of it
Torchwick，白牙，全都有
Something big is happening and no one is doing anything about it
明明有大事要發生，卻沒人做任何對策
Ozpin told us not to worry
Ozpin告訴我們不用擔心了
Between the police and the Huntsmen, I'm sure they can handle it
既有警察又有獵人，我覺得他們能搞定
Well, I'm not! They don't know the White Fang like I do
我不覺得！他們不像我這樣瞭解白牙
Okay, between blowing up nightclubs, stopping thieves and fighting for freedom
好吧，你們既砸過夜總會，抓過小偷，還為自由而戰過
I'm sure the three of you think you're all ready to go out and apprehend these ne'er do wells
我肯定你們三個已經覺得自己可以出去抓那些小混混了吧
Uh.. who?
說的..誰？
But let me once again be the voice of reason
但讓我再次理智地告訴你們
We're students
我們是學生
We're not ready to handle this sort of situation
我們還不夠能力處理這類事情
Well, yea, but..
當然，不過..
We're not ready
我們準備不足
And we may never be ready
可能根本沒機會準備充足
Our enemies aren't just gonna sit around and wait for graduation day
我們的敵人可不會坐等我們畢業那一天
They're out there somewhere, planning their next move
他們就在某處盤算著下一步行動
And none of us know what it is, but it's coming
沒人知道是什麼行動，但就要來了
Whether we're ready or not
不論我們是否準備好
Okay
好吧
All in favor of becoming the youngest Huntresses
誰支持成為史上最年輕獵人組合
to singlehandedly bring down the corrupt organization conspiring against the Kingdom of Vale
單槍匹馬干翻密謀對抗溪谷王國的邪惡組織
Say aye
說「贊」
Yes!
好！
I love it when you're feisty
我就喜歡你來勁
Well, I suppose it could be fun
好吧，應該會好玩
None of you said aye..
都沒人說「贊」..
Alright then
既然如此
We're in this together
那就一起來
Let's hatch a plan!
來制定個計劃！
Yeah!
對！
I left my board game in the library
我把棋盤遊戲忘在圖書館了
We're doomed
咱沒前途了
I'll be right back
我馬上回來
Oh God, sorry..
天哪，抱歉..
Are.. are you okay?
你..你還好吧？
I'm fine
我沒事
Just watch where you're going
走路要看路
Oh, right, sorry
哦，對，抱歉
Um, I'm Ruby
呃，我叫Ruby
Are you new?
你們是新生？
Visiting from Haven, actually
我們從黑文來訪問的
Oooh~ You're here for the festival
噢~你們來參加節日啊
Oh, but exchange students have their own dormitory
不過，交換生有自己的宿舍
I guess we just got turned around
看來是我們走錯了
Don't worry, it happens all the time
別擔心，這種事天天有
Uh, your building is just east of here
呃，你們的地方就在東邊一點兒
Thanks
謝謝
Maybe we'll see you around
也許以後還會見面
Yeah, maybe
對啊，也許吧
Oh, uh.. and welcome to Beacon!
噢，呃.. 歡迎來到信標！